so I've been thinking about uh yeah
probably the horrors by movie Harris but
and so I've got
so many ideas about it
just run see what others think
yeah there's a few suitors that's come
to mind
so on one occasion a Brahman went to the
Buddha and said to him it's astounding
and amazing Master go to my master go to
his faculties are tranquil and the color
of his skin is pure and bright
so whatever
high or luxurious
sitting place or beds there are whatever
Grand elegant Furnishings there are
Master Gautama surely gains their Med
will without trouble or difficulty in a
way you might be saying you probably
live in luxury which is why you look so
good you probably you know
things are going well for you you're
quite rich
and then he uh the Buddha replies
those high and luxurious kinds of
bedding or Furnishings are rarely
obtained by those who have gone forth
and if they are obtained they are not
allowed but Brahman there are these three kinds
but Brahman there are these three kinds
of
luxurious Furnishings that I at present
I gain at will without trouble or
difficulty the celestial luxury the Divine luxury
the celestial luxury the Divine luxury
and the noble luxury bedding
so and it just goes it says the the
celestial high and luxurious bed is
high and luxurious bed is
pajamas
that is how he travels that's where he
rests that's his uh
so so and then the um
Divine High luxurious bit is the Brahma
viharas that's how he travels where
whatever he's doing he's just dividing
in that and then the Noble High
luxurious bed is uh having been rid of
any delusion having been able to get rid
of the tanks and so on
so he's abandoned
through the banding of sensuality to the
abandoning of your will to the
abandoning of ignorance
he abides in these three different
Vehicles so to speak
so what I what I come across I'm sure
everyone has come across this thing this
advice that you you can sometimes hear someone
that you you can sometimes hear someone
say I get angry a lot with this person
left that we have
what should I do what what's the
how do I stop King saying and
advice you're here as well just practice
meta and just do that
and just do that
and I said well just just do
the celestial the celestial development
just do it you know how do you how do I
stop uh you know acting uh Century
that's John
yeah just do the genre just say it's
easy then you won't choose sensuality
anymore so it's all just be doing meta and then
so it's all just be doing meta and then
you won't
get Angry Anymore
but it is exactly the opposite way
around it's abandoning of your
sensuality a Banning of anger is how you
do matter is how you would yeah
you cannot there's two kind of practices
there's someone who's
who's actually
um
working towards
Ghana working towards the government of
the house and someone who has detained
that who has actually got that through
it and now can use it
to travel and to live his life
yeah to to vihara or biod in a charity
yeah and live
and live
but you you cannot you cannot use meta
you cannot pervade the world with matter
as long as anger is still arising if you
haven't generated you haven't grown it
you haven't developed it you cannot
cultivate it if you haven't developed it
how do you develop it
you don't just you don't just so how do
you develop this
um
so for example
if we said speaking about meta from
because I was
um there's another Suitor that says
where someone is saying I
I do meta Brown would be Harris but on
occasion you know I do get angry and the
man said well don't say that it's gone
don't miss it
that's impossible because if you have
that matter it's impossible to have your
will so why why is it possible why is it
impossible to rise
because that is the the fruit of
of abandoning you exactly what's the
definition you have abandoned ill will already so
you have abandoned ill will already so
if you say I have meta but it almost
civilizes means you have an abandonment
us you don't have much yeah and same
with John exactly same job to have
sensual thoughts arise
in the meantime every now and that's
also not possible you're either because
you abandon the centrality
but so it is quite common so I do join
us right there
no I'm not seeing from centrality but I
also believe I'm doing John and I'll be
free from centrality it means China yeah
so that it's not also again I think this
is you can either just
not do ill will
if anyone would understand that I would
say do none ill will so there's ill will
you Discerning it that may be intention
of the mind to go in that direction and
you just none it
you don't do it
but that requires a certain that you
know you need to see
what
yeah yeah you need to be able to see
your mind yeah so so I think eventually
the choice of ill will or nominal will
can become apparent but that's not the
starting point
yeah so yeah virtue is interesting and
so on seeing the mind and then having it
and specifically in regard to this it
would be you know so for example like if
you whatever would be physically done on
whatever would be physically done on
accountable well don't do it whatever
would be spoken on accountable well
don't do it then you know whatever you
if you want to think about
some something that's out of well well
don't do it yeah and then that's when
the choice and then that's what's left
is you realize oh I can uh not do this I
can drop this so to speak but not before
these three modes of expression of your
will have been thoroughly developed
um so you don't do anything in my body
you don't do anything you don't say
anything verbally then you go back
cure Solitude on your own and the mind
revolves around the four wheel well and
you recognize yeah so there is mind of
your will as we said in the this
previous talk these thoughts are the
indications of the State of Mind
so I should not feel them but I should
not try to get rid of them either
because they're not a problem
I should see that the mind is still
minor will they want to go in the
direction of these thoughts same with
centrality so I'll remain uh not
allowing it I will remain basically
watching watchful of this mind that
wants to make me distracted so then it
continues this momentum
and that's all you need to do
for how long well for as long as their
mind pressures you to go in there to to
willingly as you know accept Delight
welcome the thoughts that are presented
to you because by welcoming them you
stop seeing the mind you fall from
seeing it and now you're immersed with
thoughts so that's how you would of course that's
so that's how you would of course that's
the Southwest practice but it can be
done it's nothing like oh how can this
be achieved so you will still have the
pressure of your will you will still
have occasional thought coming up about
it but you're not taking it up and
you're certainly not trying to paste
over matter but he's a good person or
something like that because none of
that's the point
the point is mind is effective with ill
will and it's tormenting your account to
it and you're trying to fix things that
are the result of the problem not the
problem so that's the Gateway that's a Gateway
so that's the Gateway that's a Gateway
yeah if you were sufficiently then
protected a Gateway not welcome nor
denied not want only too far out you're
trying to run too far in either
then exactly you realize that the state
of the mind of your will it sound okay I
don't care not my problem and then these
thoughts won't even come
because now you have actually take the
mind now you can tell it what to do
no drop that stop it
before that you couldn't tell it you
just have to protect everything they
wanted the mind wanted to take up and
prevent the Mind from taking it up
can you say um when you said you don't
allow the mind
um
uh you could you say one way of
describing that could be to not become
absorbed in the content so exactly
that's how you've done a lot yeah yeah
so sometimes you can't as I said for as
long as you're still tormented by the
content of your thoughts
you're not seeing your mind to the
extent necessarily for this choice for
this command to work the mind is not
pliable as a student would say not yet
so the way to make it pliable is not to
okay mind stop it learn how to talk to
it no no it's too overcome any tendency
to move on account of thoughts that have
never besetting you so don't welcome
them don't they like don't open the door
don't don't go out trying to chase them
and certainly don't let them in it's
just their work it's just their evil is
there it possess one way or the other
but your responsibilities on the level
of welcoming the lighting uh picking up
all these thoughts so when that's
sufficiently endured
for as long as it takes then you are
Discerning now the state of the Mind
behind it
and sooner or later that will result in
sooner or later that will result in
obviously greater familiarity with the
phenomenon if you're on cheated on the
back the mood whatever it is and then
you can actually no no
drop that
I won't get him you know and the mind
just drops it now isn't it wonderful now
it listens to me
you might be even surprised first time
it happens
like a dog is everything yeah well he
listens to my command that I've been
repeating so long but it's always about the right
so long but it's always about the right
timing
um in the dog training and you realize
this is the same yeah you can't just be
saying it to your mind like a mantra and
somehow magically could pick up no no no
no
you got to do it rightly I mean the time
is right when these things are not being
um when you are not distracted by these
things you're not you're not trying to
get rid of the thoughts or welcome them
and so on and now is the right time now
you recognize the mind is pliable let me
now direct it away from you son also and
that's pretty much when you start
boarding the vehicle of meta and so on
because the anger cannot over one cannot
enter you anymore
by speech by mind now those have been
purified oh look now you are in control
of this vehicle that you can take it
away from any direction available
or Jana take it away from any direction
of hindrances and centrality for example
for example
a like a very broadly speaking practical
like a thought of ill will is always to
some extent on the level of
so and so did something bad to me or
just did something bad
and then usually if you have this kind
of view of matter or even just generally
actually if you say oh no I shouldn't be
angry with that person the natural thing
that's the thing the thought of their
will you realize yeah so I don't need to get
you realize yeah so I don't need to get
rid of that it is behind the thought of
ill will he's an angry mind and if you
developed you tell that mind in the back
to drop it not the thought you don't
deal with the thought
and if the Mind drops it the thought of
ill will it's not the ill will anymore
it's just a thought of factually
somebody did something exactly there is
no ill will in its core that's what I
was getting at because you know a lot of
the time then you'd find yourself people
trying to sort of
like reconstitute what somebody did
oh it wasn't that bad or I understand
and that's all totally kind of
misguided and released a lot of because
it always asking you over overlooking
where the where the mind is where the
problem is and you want to deal with the
thought explain the thought give it a
little bit it's like that's not that's
not the point
it's the state of mind and get back
and even sometimes if their mind doesn't
listen to you like that it says oh he
crushes his mind with the mind people
often tend that to me now I stop
thinking see he said no
you crashed the mind with the mind which
means if you still think it's about a
thought you're not even seeing their
mind how can you crush it context how
can you stand your ground against it
when you're not even seeing it
so it's the ultimate contest the
ultimate peripheral
oh that's where the mind is and yeah
Crush that leave these thoughts
irrelevant just overpower that man over
there and nothing can bother you on a
specific level
the master of thought so it's not just
some sort of management technique or is
this I think that one is this this is
this when you say I stand up and it's
like yeah good luck with that
it's very I mean
like it's very relevant or it's not uh
it's relevant to the problem of of
suffering and freedom from suffering
obviously but in specifically also
because you know when there's ill will so and so
you know when there's ill will so and so
did something bad
naturally the kind of the view of of
anger or ill will is I'm suffering
because of what this person did
but it's like if you see genuinely that
the only reason you're suffering is
actually because of the ill will the ill
will is the suffering of it then there's
literally no reason to there's there's
no basis for ill will anymore because
there's the you know what this other
person did so what did you do then is
irrelevant you realize you need to
refrain from jumping back into making it
from jumping back into making it
personal when you know it's not about it
you know it's the presence of a world
that's bothering but still let me just
yes so it's like oh so lack of restraint
he's wide area will prolifer it's not
because of who said what and because of
what you didn't say in return and so on
all that's irrelevant
Washington state do in fact states that
by developing meta for example it will
come to dependence but the context there
is a normal disciple already has quite
view who already see what we just
described knows what meta is and it's
uprooting the factor of your will
the possibility that that is ever going
to arise in the future yeah that and
that gets them mistaken for the idea oh
content matter is is instantly available
regardless of that I now available I can
apply that as an antidote to the ill
will but it's overlooked that that's
dealing with a fatter and and that's a
so different context yeah yeah and also
as we just said abandoning of ill will
is what the Practical matter is so
develop matter to abandon your will
let you develop abandoning of your will
to not have real will
that's what it is
so it's not another positive thing you
do in regard in response to their will
so if there is still possibility of mine
going back into their will developmental
further develop the Narnia will further
yeah same with centrality yeah that's why the
same with centrality yeah that's why the
first genre is necessary for an anagami
or another hunt I the noble disciple
another who are free from Central
desires it's necessary in a sense of by
abandoning sensuality by seeing the
danger the palette withdrawing from it
tatsujana so cultivate that experience
that's free from sensuality long enough
and possibility for returning back to it
will disappear and equally possibility
for taking things personally and turning
it back into misconceiving it will also
disappear and that's what it will describe and yes
and that's what it will describe and yes
the dwelling in Jannah is is blame is
it's it's pure it's it's it's uh
it's to be developed and then I tell
monk okay monk now regard that
blamelessness when you walk go to toilet
whatever else regard that as the battle
the debt the dark subject impermanence
you're suffering and all of that and the
mind will completely so when the Mind
turns away
doesn't want anything to do with the
purified experience of Janna how can it
possibly conceive returning back to like
started a thousand times closer and worse such
a thousand times closer and worse such
essentiality and ill will it becomes
impreciable and that's how demand is
free
this is yeah
the the phrase that you often read in
suit is is uh
live regarding One Direction with a mind
endowed with meta likewise the second
the third the fourth Direction thus
above below a cross and everywhere and
to all as to myself I live regarding the
entire world of the Mind endowed with
meta vast exalted unobstructed without
hostility without a will
but you can only do that
when you have when you are without
hostility and without you so so one one
who has the matter then
then can start doing this
yeah make it a vehicle for breakfast
yeah and
regard the world
so in all directions with that that mind
that's unobstructed
how do you how do you lose that that
state of mind can it be can it happen
accidentally no you have to
can it happen just like you know he was
so careful and you know what happened
next thing is gone
impossible so you lose it but become
careless ah so I lose it through my own actions
ah so I lose it through my own actions
that take me away from it
so you need to protect it from yourself
trim it on underlying tendencies
yeah sensuality breaking prison yes yeah
acting out I mean
so I'll just read another Suitor The
Meta Suitor and this is basically
instructions for protection of that
right and and it begins with this is what
and and it begins with this is what
should be done by what by those who are
skilled in goodness
and fully understand the path of Peace
yeah skilled in goodness means knowing
wholesalers at least so so by those who have the
at least so so by those who have the
right View
they are so how what do you do this is
what you do to protect that they are
capable upright or very upright good
speech gentle not prideful content easy
to support
unbusied with the duties through your
email address peaceful faculties clever
not intrusive or greedy amongst families
not doing the slightest thing that the
wise would find fault with
not doing the slightest thing routine
ingredient distraction
I'll just skip to the middle of this
Suitor not acting against nor despising
anyone anywhere
even when irritated by the perception of
patiga resistance not wishing suffering
on anyone
even as a mother would protect her only
beneficial child so too should all
beings cultivate
the unobstructed mind
with meta towards the entire world
cultivate an unobstructed mind above
below or around unconfined friendly and
without enemies
with a standing walking sitting or lying
down not becoming wary always
remembering this for this is the way of
the cards yeah
attained to view accomplished in insight
and virtue freed from the expelling of
sensual desire they never again are
conceived in the womb hmm
so the the part that I left out it's a
kind of I just find it a strange but the
middle part it's kind of a
thought and
it goes happy and secure may all beings
be happy whatever living beings there
are whatever they are
may all beings be happy yes so it's a
kind of a
and in a way this is a this is like
everything else is no whatever but take
this and just repeat that Mantra make
all things go wrong
so I can't leave it out but yeah that is
I'm not saying it's invalid
it's not really practices yes it's the
fruit again
it's good it's kind of funny actually I
mean because
I think what you kind of recognize is
like whether I wish it or not I can't I
can't make other beings be well and
that's not the point it's just not to
like not that's not where yeah wear
anger yeah if you are doing you're not
acting out of anger well
other beings in that sense are going to
be well I mean you're not going to be
causing issues
you're not going to be causing issues if
you cannot act out of anger if you're
protecting their mind you can't even act
out around yeah you can't even have act
out of uh speak out of anger and so on
you wouldn't be evolving on the thoughts
of anger either so it's like yeah that's
the the greatest protection you can give to
the greatest protection you can give to
others well
no education not not taking it
personally
not irritated by the perception of
resistance of any kind yeah and that's
what agreeable disagreeable yeah and
that's like the whole the core of drama
behind practices you know the practice
of non-resistance and on ill will and
just refining it refining refining it is
so
not your will no because that's stupid
because the ultimate of abandoning of
Patika yeah the slightest races of
Latina so it's a complete non-resistance or
so it's a complete non-resistance or
hmm
craving in that sense towards pain
where does pain arise where does the
resistance arise as well you
fundamentally resisting
this body the discomfort of it so in a
way you would
that's where you can start that's
non-resistance to this
being here which is giving you some sort
of pressure some kind of irritation yeah
you're giving you you know uh that show
kind of
your
the first being
the first living being which you could
you have your will towards you know the
rest of the first protocol will so to
speak yeah the self-love yeah and if you
self-loathe and hate or have ill will
towards this in your face discomfort
that's right here then for sure you're
going to be the next out there that's
that's guaranteed and if somebody were
to say well we're ready
um
I don't self-load I'm completely free
from self-loathing
but they still have Central desires and
they go through it's interesting would
that be a valid statement
is because you're avoiding the the
discomfort the patiga the resistance of
this these senses unsatisfied seemingly
um I mean as I say seemingly because
unsatisfied sense is real as such and
it's only unsatisfied from your
projection projective your satisfaction
in and of itself it's fine for what it
is itch does not require a script you
imply is correct
yeah
so so for as long as somebody is still
attracted to sensuality to that extent
they still resist this body yeah that's
the cool thing yeah yeah so if you can
so start there yeah you won't be
approving any other ill will externally
if you're not approaching the patiga
internally and you will know you're recruiting
and you will know you're recruiting
internally if you're abandoning desires
to attend pleasures and that's exactly
why sensuality and ill will an abandon
hand in hand
so in a way if someone was interested in
practicing caring proper caring for all beings
caring proper caring for all beings
myself and everyone in my world because
that was your inclination you could you
know well I again I want to develop
great compassion and care for everything
well then you you shouldn't you need to
know what's unbeneficial what's
beneficial be clear on it and then start
to
do what is beneficial for this being
here first because if you don't sort
this one out well you've got no
perspective you can't you can't help
anyone else if you're hurting the very
the one that's closest to you well
you might be helping that other being
over there to some degree but still your
mind is
it's a abstracted mind really it's
narrowed and on the basis of your ear
will towards this I don't care about
myself okay but that's the basis is hatred
okay but that's the basis is hatred
still you're you're careful all others
is based upon a resistance to what's
here yeah so it's not obstructed you're
a narrow-minded basically you have no
perspective what is good for others
in a way you know see the other this
being here as a
your child that you would look after
someone who dear to you that you would
okay somebody relevant somebody that
needs help in a way that they don't
necessarily know it
they don't know what's good for them but
you know what's good for them yeah and
that's already you and it's quite
irrelevant because if this person is uh
agitated and upset and going through
loads of paintball
you're feeling it you're the one feeling
you're the one experiencing so yes it is
relevant well that's that the whole like
the the single suitable and suitable
food for the wound or for the animal
for the wound or for the animal
depending on the simile but the point is
it's like yeah this creature here this
individual I don't need to know why he likes this
I don't need to know why he likes this
why he doesn't like that why his mind
responds like this when it's that why I
need to just recognize that it is so and
then directed away from things that
aggravate the condition of last aversion
and distraction towards things that that
come the last aversion distraction yeah
but I need to I don't need to know why
it's not my problem why this horse has
such a preference why are they sending
my likes that my problem is then I pay
with it so if it's agitated I'll have to
suffer if it's gripped by favorite last I have
if it's gripped by favorite last I have
to suffer the consequences if it's
distracted it's on me again
so that's when you recognize that space
between you and your own mind so to
speak when you see it as a creature that
needs taming that does not necessarily
know what's best for it
but you you don't need to even figure
out why is that so all you need to do is
stick to the fact that well if it's
educated I'll pay the price so that's
all I care about I'll keep it calm so it
doesn't bother me
and that's that that that kind of the
first point of view recognition so if
you have no ill will towards this
creature and you will have no availability with
and you will have no availability with
this creature you will have no
resistance to this creature if you have
started taming it then withdrawing it
from the expressions of real will and
patiga which are sensuality expression
essentiality then you can actually
protect it rightly you can have a
context and you don't need to teach it
or explain to it what's happening you
just need to direct it away from the
unsuitable pastures and keep it in the
suitable ones and it will start to
listen to you because then eventually
even a creature will awake to itself and
recognize oh yeah no this is actually
what I always want to thank you by the
way I I you know I could not see it but
you you took me away from the
unwholesome stuff and now things are
clear yeah essentially it was always a
boil a pain a charcoal pit it was
torture but I didn't know that
thank you for keeping me away now I know
it and then you can let go of it because
you won't go back there because he was
truly not pleasant even back then but he
doesn't know and that's that whole kind
of discrepancy the people would feel and
said yeah but I know that it's
unpleasant but I can't help it see the
problem is that they are identified
with the with the mind they don't see
the mind so they're automatically to
possession took the point of view so
they think they want it
so one and they know that it's not
suitable and that it's resulting always
always resulting in pain but then when
the pressure comes they cannot not
identify with the pressure so I want it
and then they go back to it it's like
even if I want it I'll put what I know
first and what I know first is this is not
and what I know first is this is not
suitable
but I want it doesn't matter you sustain
that long enough you will start seeing
the difference between wanting it and me
being that wanting you just there is
wanting but there is perspective there
is body exactly there is the
naturopathyroid of the body there are 10
Tendencies of the senses but by now I am
not automatically identified with them
because I actually sustained and
protected them from going into that
unwholesome food in areas they were
perpetuating and aggravating this
identification and confusion and that's like beginning
and confusion and that's like beginning
to see the signs of your mind means
beginning to see this beginning to
develop this unidentification with your
own point of view you recognize it it is
so
I see it I see what it leads to but I
still am able to now emphasize the
restraint or the perspective and not
automatically just merge with it and
directed by it
yeah that's yeah right view seeing yeah
this body is not not self yourself so
you can by just adopting that
view of this that creature over here you
know that creature
over there
now you're already doing this separation
non-identification at the same time well
that's being developed but again to
qualify because somebody might hear this
and then they think they can just jump
right into that part of the practice
I'll just keep seeing this is a creature
and saying it's not mine that comes
well you can do that theoretically that
will basically start to apply and take
root correctly concretely only if you
are and have been restrained beforehand
and kept yourself withdrawn from the
floods of sensuality and ill will
and then these oh this is not mine oh
actually yeah look it's not mine the
dimension of it becomes clearer you can
consider it as you can consider it but
you have to see it is going to come as a
result of the right withdrawal yeah you
can't induce the withdrawal through just
telling to yourself that this is not
mine it will just result in dismissing
the responsibility for the actions that
are yours because you are identified
yeah so yeah what do I what's good for
me what should I do what should I
shouldn't I do am I doing that yeah
refining the right way then you can get
a perspective and regards yourself as
another creature exactly you know it's just a
creature exactly you know it's just a
very close one the closest to this point
of view yeah and
and then
being accomplished in that in some of
some degree you that lawlessly spill out
well exactly because the only way you
can actually have sympathy with anybody
this this creature over here that
creature over there are just the
creature example and the experience of other
example and the experience of other
creatures agreeable or disagreeable
experience of others can only be
experienced on account of patiga of this
scripture so if you're witnessing somebody who is
so if you're witnessing somebody who is
who is unpleasant there is patiga felt
here this creature is feeling the
discomfort of that person
not me so if you developed in regard to
this patiga here no amount of discomfort
caused by others can cause you pain
because again the entry point for it
the patiga here is something you're
fully developed in regard to you cannot
overwhelm it kind of overpower you you
cannot lose perspective when I can't do
it
so by by protecting this creature
you are protected Against All Creatures
and you're protecting them so you are
developing the sympathy that you know
yeah compassionate
and then furthering that is just uh what
mudita no non-tentiousness is hard to
translate it or blending like knowing
the benefits for both hear this creature
and that creature over there you know
blending like milk well imagine now if
we are all here individually internally
unable to to to be overwhelmed resist against
to to to be overwhelmed resist against
act out of the our patiga of our own
creatures so if you are fully attained India
so if you are fully attained India
there's not a slightest traces of
resistance towards the creature that you are now
towards the creature that you are now
slightly stress and resistance to the
creature you have and same for everybody
this assembly would be completely
blending like milk and water there will
be no distinction because there is no
basis for any discrepancy
so whatever somebody else do
does in here in the group none of the
group could take that internally through their
could take that internally through their
own particularly they are not developed
in regard to
so there will be no ripples internally
regardless of what so that's a perfect
harmony because everybody's incapable
of resisting the creature that they are
and they might not be saying much
we might appreciate you today
yeah yeah but you you wouldn't need to
be well you you can't express this
external no amount of external
expression of
um gratitude and so on means anything to
whether the fact that you are still
moved by your own resistance in regard
to your own creature or not
so whether you're saying it or not it's
irrelevant yeah
you might say if somebody asks you to
answer a question but you wouldn't say
believing that through saying it you're
doing it
no that's just the verb statements well
yeah that's wishful thinking yeah oh may
my chick spear sound yes see I always
express my wish every morning I pray to
the shrine and I say may ill will not
arise in me well whether you wish or not
are you doing the work on the level of
self-loading withdrawing from sensuality
not acting out a little will or not well
that's that you'll get your answer
have always remind you that similarly of
the the the hen and the chicks
oh made my chicks Pierce out safely from
the shell but she doesn't sit on her
eggs well they won't even if she wishes
for the rest of her life every moment of
her life if she just prays that they
appears out they won't because she's not
doing the work
and the other
type of hand who sits on the on the XG
even if she doesn't wish
made their pears out safely into this
world they will they will come to to to
to grow and so on because she did the
work so also if you just said between passing
so also if you just said between passing
like if you practice this rightly you
will see your own sense of self as other
and then all other others actual factor
or others will be already on that side
of you seeing yourself as other yeah so
even further others yeah it's just
further away but still it's that it's
that one dimension so yeah so when that
Center speaks about you know one quarter
here at the and so on it seems to me
it's describing a certain kind of
totality because it is division between
the identification which is me and
others is now changed on the counter
seeing that your sense of self is no
longer yours so it's sort of there and
that is already there or others were
yeah so cultivate meta in that sense
towards Yourself rightly by disowning
your experience basically and the whole
thing is this answer yeah exactly
exactly yeah yeah it was in the same
principle in regardless of patanas
knowing the bodies there the body is the
world so seeing this creature in its
totality uh fully developing in regard
to its own patiga
is basically the world of others
everything everything is within it
so that direction this direction up down
every way it's within that creature
and then that then leads to the complete
the fourth the
opacism the slightest races of resistance left
the slightest races of resistance left
in the alternative
so see now it's even not anymore on the
level of this creature those creatures
personal in person let me just
resistance and absence of it complete
purification and movement of the traces
yeah
just need to come back briefly soon
that point about I just wanted to maybe
emphasize a little bit more that
about sympathy or compassion being like
really the results of first developing
non-ill will non-resistance you know in
regard to yourself your own creature
towards others generally rather than
in other words like you know you you
said at one point you know you can have
the inclination to care for people or
you know to want to care for the world
generally or to be sympathetic with
others but that's if you haven't developed
but that's if you haven't developed
non-ill will that's not actually going
to be genuine Symphony if you don't have
understanding of what's generally
beneficial and unbeneficial and have
developed that in regard to yourself
your sympathy will be kind of on the
level of I sympathize with people who
are unhappy because of circumstances or
something but you won't really understand if you
but you won't really understand if you
don't understand where suffering comes
from and have understood that and
developed that in yourself then you
can't really be sympathetic on the right
level with people who you know on in or
with anybody or with anything
because yeah your kind of sympathy is
already based on a on a perversion of
the idea of why they're why they are
unhappy or why they are suffering
um
so
so yeah I think that's kind of important
to to note that like you can't
you don't you shouldn't even worry or
think about trying to be have compassion
or be sympathetic really towards others
unless you've first
basically unders understood
suffering but then you would be
automatically and then you'd
automatically wouldn't need to think
about sympathizing with others it's more
like uh if you wanted to help you get
straight to the point yeah well you
would actually know what yeah
well it's helpful and to what extent
help is possible
yeah exactly